[
  {
    "no": "01",
    "question": "What is Flutter?",
    "options": [
      "A music streaming platform",
      "A mobile development framework",
      "A photo editing software",
      "A video conferencing tool"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A mobile development framework"
  },
  {
    "no": "02",
    "question": "Which programming language is primarily used in Flutter?",
    "options": ["Java", "Python", "Dart", "Swift"],
    "correctAnswer": "Dart"
  },
  {
    "no": "03",
    "question": "What does Flutter use for rendering UI?",
    "options": ["XML", "HTML", "Canvas", "OpenGL"],
    "correctAnswer": "Canvas"
  },
  {
    "no": "04",
    "question": "What is a 'Widget' in Flutter?",
    "options": [
      "A small furry creature",
      "A component for building UI",
      "A data storage mechanism",
      "A type of animation"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A component for building UI"
  },
  {
    "no": "05",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'setState()' in Flutter?",
    "options": [
      "To define the state of an app",
      "To reset the app to its initial state",
      "To update the UI based on state changes",
      "To import external libraries"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To update the UI based on state changes"
  },
  {
    "no": "06",
    "question": "What is the main function of the 'pubspec.yaml' file in Flutter projects?",
    "options": [
      "To specify project dependencies",
      "To define UI layouts",
      "To configure device permissions",
      "To store user preferences"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To specify project dependencies"
  },
  {
    "no": "07",
    "question": "What does the 'hot reload' feature in Flutter do?",
    "options": [
      "Reboots the device",
      "Compiles the entire project from scratch",
      "Updates the app's UI without restarting the app",
      "Uninstalls the app"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Updates the app's UI without restarting the app"
  },
  {
    "no": "08",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'Navigator' in Flutter?",
    "options": [
      "To navigate between app screens",
      "To control device settings",
      "To manage network requests",
      "To create animations"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To navigate between app screens"
  },
  {
    "no": "09",
    "question": "Which IDEs are commonly used for Flutter development?",
    "options": [
      "Visual Studio Code and IntelliJ IDEA",
      "Eclipse and Android Studio",
      "Xcode and Atom",
      "Sublime Text and NetBeans"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Visual Studio Code and IntelliJ IDEA"
  },
  {
    "no": "10",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'async' and 'await' keywords in Flutter?",
    "options": [
      "To define variables",
      "To handle asynchronous operations",
      "To perform mathematical calculations",
      "To create custom animations"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To handle asynchronous operations"
  }
]
